<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Kevin Galligan Blog</title>
        <link>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Kevin Galligan Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[oss-updates]]></title>
            <link>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/03/10/oss-updates</link>
            <guid>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/03/10/oss-updates</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We've been heads down for the last few months working on our new professional offerings: SKIE and Touchlab Pro. We'll be posting about them soon. While that work has been the major focus, our open source projects have been mostly getting critical updates. As our new projects have been nearing release, we've finished a bunch of updates to our open source libraries.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Open Source Updates</h1><p>We've been heads down for the last few months working on our new professional offerings: <a href="https://get.touchlab.co/skie-touchlab-pro/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SKIE and Touchlab Pro</a>. We'll be posting about them soon. While that work has been the major focus, our open source projects have been mostly getting critical updates. As our new projects have been nearing release, we've finished a bunch of updates to our open source libraries.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="kmmbridge"><a href="https://kmmbridge.touchlab.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KMMBridge</a><a href="#kmmbridge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to kmmbridge" title="Direct link to kmmbridge">​</a></h2><p>We've had a few tweaks and updates pending for some time. Those have been pushed with version <a href="https://github.com/touchlab/KMMBridge/releases/tag/0.3.7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">0.3.7</a>.</p><p>One of the less visible but really important changes is a flag that disables a lot of the "stuff" that needs to happen when actually publishing versions. If you opened a project with earlier versions of KMMBridge on a dev machine, several things might happen in the background that really don't need to. Now they won't.</p><p>Also, if you happen to use S3 as your publish target, there's a bug in the default AWS SDK. This version should fix that for you.</p><p>Finally, the website has been updated: <a href="https://kmmbridge.touchlab.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">kmmbridge.touchlab.co</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="kermit"><a href="https://kermit.touchlab.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kermit</a><a href="#kermit" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to kermit" title="Direct link to kermit">​</a></h2><p>Kermit's API has gone through a fairly significant update. We've released <a href="https://github.com/touchlab/Kermit/releases/tag/2.0.0-RC3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2.0.0-RC3</a> with the new changes. Feedback is welcome.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-api">New API<a href="#new-api" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New API" title="Direct link to New API">​</a></h3><p>1.x versions had a <code>Logger</code> API that was designed to be called from non-Kotlin environments. For the most part, that meant avoiding default parameters. However, the primary use case is calling from Kotlin. The primary <code>Logger</code> API was updated to be (mostly) source compatible, but now include simpler method definitions with default parameters.</p><p>In simple terms, that means all log calls can have message, a <code>Throwable</code>, and a tag specified.</p><p>For non-Kotlin environments such as Swift and JS, you can export <code>kermit-simple</code>, which provides extension methods to make calling less verbose from those environments (without default parameter support, you'd need to provide each value on each call).</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="custom-api">Custom API<a href="#custom-api" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Custom API" title="Direct link to Custom API">​</a></h3><p>We had a lot of feedback about Kermit's API decisions since releasing it. Some has been incorporated, but some is really just personal preference. For example, full names instead of single letter methods for logging calls (<code>info()</code> instead of <code>i()</code>). You can't make everybody happy.</p><p>However, most of the functionality has been moved to the module <code>kermit-core</code>. The <code>kemrit</code> module is now fairly small, and just represents the public <code>Logger</code> API. That means you can add your own <code>Logger</code> API on top of the Kermit internals. See <a href="https://kermit.touchlab.co/docs/details/CUSTOM_API" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Custom Logger API</a> for more detail.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="website-update">Website Update<a href="#website-update" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Website Update" title="Direct link to Website Update">​</a></h3><p>And, of course, the website has been updated: <a href="https://kermit.touchlab.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">kermit.touchlab.co</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="crashkios"><a href="https://crashkios.touchlab.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CrashKiOS</a><a href="#crashkios" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to crashkios" title="Direct link to crashkios">​</a></h2><p>CrashKiOS has had an interesting history. The library allows Crashlytics and Bugsnag to report symbolicated Kotlin crash reports on iOS (and other Darwin/Apple targets). Most of this functionality was moved into Kermit as we had several requests to support Kermit integration.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="changes">Changes<a href="#changes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Changes" title="Direct link to Changes">​</a></h3><p>However, crash reporting has other features unrelated to logging, such as custom key/value pairs, and automatically catching hard crashes. Also, <a href="https://github.com/rickclephas/NSExceptionKt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NSExceptionKt</a> tweaked the method being used for reporting hard crashes. This allows reports to be consolidated rather than the earlier dual report method.</p><p>The crash reporting details from Kermit have been moved back into CrashKiOS, and various parts of <code>NSExceptionKt</code> have been integrated, to support crash reporting as a standalone library again. Kermit's support has been simplified. You can add log writers for Crashlytics or Bugsnag, but they both delegate to CrashKiOS.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-website">New Website<a href="#new-website" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New Website" title="Direct link to New Website">​</a></h3><p>Website also updated: <a href="https://crashkios.touchlab.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">crashkios.touchlab.co</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="stately"><a href="https://github.com/touchlab/Stately" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stately</a><a href="#stately" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to stately" title="Direct link to stately">​</a></h2><p>Stately was designed to help developers work with the original strict memory model of Kotlin/Native. That memory model has been deprecated. We've released <a href="https://github.com/touchlab/Stately/releases/tag/1.2.5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one last version of the original Stately</a> built on 1.8.0, for teams that aren't ready to update everything and who would like to continue using Stately as it was in earlier Kotlin versions.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-now">What Now?<a href="#what-now" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What Now?" title="Direct link to What Now?">​</a></h3><p>Since the strict memory model has been deprecated, Stately's future has been up in the air. We internally still find some of the concurrency pieces useful, and with the new memory model, there are some utility classes we wanted to have available. It is likely that newer libraries will better handle these cases in the future, but we've added them to Stately for now.</p><p><code>stately-concurrency</code> contains structures like locks and atomics. There is functionality similar to Atomic-Fu, and we may eventually deprecate this support in Stately, but for now we continue to use it in our projects.</p><p><code>stately-strict</code> contains shared definitions of things like <code>freeze()</code>. This is only for use in projects that still have this code in their projects and don't want to remove it. Most projects will be running on the new memory model, and <code>freeze()</code> won't really do anything.</p><p><code>stately-concurrent-collections</code> is a simple implementation of thread-safe collections. We anticipate somebody will eventually release something more robust, but for now, you can easily include this module to have shared collections in your project.</p><p>Stately did <em>not</em> get a website refresh. The future utility of Stately is up in the air, so we didn't prioritize the website update.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="documentation-sites">Documentation Sites<a href="#documentation-sites" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Documentation Sites" title="Direct link to Documentation Sites">​</a></h2><p>We've moved several of our open source projects' documentation to <a href="https://docusaurus.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Docusaurus</a>. I have been pretty skeptical of these kinds of site generators, but finally took a look at Docusaurus after several team members mentioned it as an option.</p><p>It is one of my favorite things now. I've even moved my personal site to Docusaurus, just for the blog.</p><p>There's too much going on to explain <em>why</em> I love it, but some highlights (some Docusaurus-specific, some just neat hacks)</p><ul><li>Docusaurus let's you create custom react components and use them directly in markdown, so we can extend the markdown syntax easily</li><li>Dark and light mode</li><li>Code style is highly customizable. Kotlin code has Intellij/Android Studio colors, while Swift looks like Xcode (see <a href="https://kermit.touchlab.co/docs/configuration/NON_KOTLIN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kermit docs</a>)</li><li>Our doc build process auto-replaces version strings into code samples. This isn't Dosusaurus specific, but a nice add on. The CI process gets the latest published release string and replaces a template string in the markdown. Anything in <code>gradle.properties</code> can be swapped as well.</li></ul><p>It's easy to tweak and extend. It's just great.</p><p>The home page of each doc site is now using a simple react template (from <a href="https://cruip.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cruip.com</a>). That uses tailwind CSS, which is the other new (to me) web thing I'm in love with now. Although there's <a href="https://github.com/facebook/docusaurus/issues/2961" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">been discussion</a>, Docusaurus doesn't have a tailwind theme, so the CSS is bit of a blended hack. Once you get started, though, its really easy to develop with it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Medical Update]]></title>
            <link>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/02/28/medical-update</link>
            <guid>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/02/28/medical-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Last Thursday, 9 days ago, I had some life firsts. I couldn't walk, because my legs basically didn't work. That was new. Had to call 911, for the first time, because if I couldn't walk I couldn't stay in our apartment. I was rolled out into an ambulance. First ambulance ride, at least for me as the primary passenger.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Thursday, 9 days ago, I had some life firsts. I couldn't walk, because my legs basically didn't work. That was new. Had to call 911, for the first time, because if I couldn't walk I couldn't stay in our apartment. I was rolled out into an ambulance. First ambulance ride, at least for me as the primary passenger.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Ambulance" src="/assets/images/ambulance-330648e6b022312756e2239c04342598.jpg" width="1512" height="1475" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>This is after gradually losing muscle strength since late December and early January. It started with needing two hands to pour coffee because I couldn't lift the caraffe. Things progessively got worse, to the point where I got a rollator so I could go further than a block from our apartment. I decorated it with a Motorhead shirt for a night out.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Motorrollator" src="/assets/images/motorrollo-2999fd27956075f36514bdf793d78bae.jpg" width="1512" height="1030" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>I was diagnosed with Psoriatic Arthritis a year ago and started medications to deal with that. At its worst, the arthritis also caused some hand weakness, so I figured it was the same thing. I was switching PsA meds at the same time.</p><p>By late January, it was obviously not the arthritis. I tried getting into a neurologist, but the first availabilities were around June/July. Another doctor made some calls and got an appointment for 2/28, so I just needed to hold out for a few weeks.</p><p>By last Wednesday, getting in and out of bed was difficult, and I could only type about one sentence before I had to stop. Needed two hands to brush my teeth. That kind of thing.</p><p>Thursday morning, it took a few minutes to actually stand up, then I immediately fell. On the way down, there was a loud crack from my leg. After laying there for a bit, it seemed like I maybe sprained my ankle, but nothing was broken. I crawled out to the rollator, then sat to figure out what to do next.</p><p>I couldn't walk. I couldn't safely get into our bathroom. So, staying in the apartment seemed like a bad plan. We wound up calling 911 and getting an ambulance.</p><p>Thankfully, I was able to choose hospitals, so I went to NYU. All of my doctors are in the NYU system, and their Neurology program is ranked top in the country, so I figured that was the best place to go.</p><p>That was Thursday morning. There were no rooms, so I stayed in the ER until Friday afternoon, but other than that, care was excellent. In total, I had a spine MRI, CT scan, chest X-Ray, lumbar puncture (would not recommend that), and at least 10 blood test draws. Friday afternoon, I was moved into the 2nd best hospital room I've ever seen, and only because the other one was 2-3 times as big. Everything else about this room was better. The view, 65" TV, tablet for controlling the TV, ordering food, controlling lights and temp, etc.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Tv and window" src="/assets/images/tv_window-2a83898e00aedd034d796548b6fdfe35.jpg" width="2016" height="1512" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Night view" src="/assets/images/nightview-358748d32e061773f88c14f10aadb020.jpg" width="2016" height="1512" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Sunrise" src="/assets/images/morning_sunrise-09b618cd70c8e95906041e2527296b07.jpg" width="2016" height="1512" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Tablet" src="/assets/images/tablet-37a6d929a5d90b3b5a5042fabd1c9540.jpg" width="2016" height="1512" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Originally I was going to stay through Tuesday, but recovery was so quick they let me out Sunday. While I was certainly happy to go home, by Sunday I was basically fine. That room would be pretty amazing if you could get around easily :)</p><p>Anyway, after all that, the diagnosis was <a href="https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/conditions-and-diseases/chronic-inflammatory-demyelinating-polyradiculoneuropathy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CIDP</a>. It's an autoimmune condition where your body attacks the myelin sheath around your neurons. There's no obvious "test" for that, except for the collection of symptoms and some test markers. There are several other pretty terrible things that my symptoms could've suggested (ALS, etc), but I was extremely lucky on that front.</p><p>It's relatively rare, and probably caused by whatever respiratory virus I had mid December. Apparently what seems like a normal "cold" can trigger a response like this in rare cases.</p><p>I had 3 infusions of IVIG: Friday night, Saturday night, and Sunday afternoon. After the first one, Saturday morning, my hands were useful again, and I could get around with the walker. On Sunday, I could walk without the walker.</p><p><a href="https://www.webmd.com/a-to-z-guides/immunoglobulin-therapy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IVIG</a> is interesting. It's made from processed blood donations. I haven't done the Google-based medical research enough to understand it, but let's just say it was magic. And if you can donate blood, please do so.</p><p>On Tuesday, 2/28, I went to that Neurology appointment. The doctor said it might be AIDP rather than CIDP. The difference is "Acute" vs "Chronic". If it's "Acute", then I might be done. Chronic would mean IVIG every month or two, but we'll cross fingers on "Acute". Even if "chronic", it's not a big deal.</p><p>My hand and leg strength as of Wednesday, 6 days after the fall, seemed completely back to normal (except atrophy from lack of use, which should be built back up quickly). </p><p>So, Thursday, can't walk or use my hands. 5-6 days later, back to normal. 2023 has already been pretty wild.</p><p>Please donate blood. That's how they make IVIG. Also, a huge thanks to the NYU medical team. Everybody was amazing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello!]]></title>
            <link>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/02/16/Well-Hello</link>
            <guid>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/02/16/Well-Hello</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I no longer remember how many "new blog" posts I've written, but here's another one.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I no longer remember how many "new blog" posts I've written, but here's another one.</p><p>Over the past year I've learned quite a bit about <a href="https://docusaurus.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Docusaurus</a>. It's safe to say at this point that I love it. Markdown everything! Easy react extensions. Open source. It's fantastic.</p><p>We're slowly moving Touchlab open source repos to Docusaurus. Besides better formatting and navigation, we also do a little trick to place the latest library version directly in the docs.</p><p>The home page for this site is just react with tailwind as the CSS library. It would be great if Docusaurus had a tailwind template, but for now I've hacked everything to let the two systems reasonably coexist.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>