<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Kevin Galligan Blog</title>
        <link>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Kevin Galligan Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Medical Update]]></title>
            <link>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/02/28/medical-update</link>
            <guid>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/02/28/medical-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Last Thursday, 9 days ago, I had some life firsts. I couldn't walk, because my legs basically didn't work. That was new. Had to call 911, for the first time, because if I couldn't walk I couldn't stay in our apartment. I was rolled out into an ambulance. First ambulance ride, at least for me as the primary passenger.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Thursday, 9 days ago, I had some life firsts. I couldn't walk, because my legs basically didn't work. That was new. Had to call 911, for the first time, because if I couldn't walk I couldn't stay in our apartment. I was rolled out into an ambulance. First ambulance ride, at least for me as the primary passenger.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Ambulance" src="/assets/images/ambulance-330648e6b022312756e2239c04342598.jpg" width="1512" height="1475" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>This is after gradually losing muscle strength since late December and early January. It started with needing two hands to pour coffee because I couldn't lift the caraffe. Things progessively got worse, to the point where I got a rollator so I could go further than a block from our apartment. I decorated it with a Motorhead shirt for a night out.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Motorrollator" src="/assets/images/motorrollo-2999fd27956075f36514bdf793d78bae.jpg" width="1512" height="1030" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>I was diagnosed with Psoriatic Arthritis a year ago and started medications to deal with that. At its worst, the arthritis also caused some hand weakness, so I figured it was the same thing. I was switching PsA meds at the same time.</p><p>By late January, it was obviously not the arthritis. I tried getting into a neurologist, but the first availabilities were around June/July. Another doctor made some calls and got an appointment for 2/28, so I just needed to hold out for a few weeks.</p><p>By last Wednesday, getting in and out of bed was difficult, and I could only type about one sentence before I had to stop. Needed two hands to brush my teeth. That kind of thing.</p><p>Thursday morning, it took a few minutes to actually stand up, then I immediately fell. On the way down, there was a loud crack from my leg. After laying there for a bit, it seemed like I maybe sprained my ankle, but nothing was broken. I crawled out to the rollator, then sat to figure out what to do next.</p><p>I couldn't walk. I couldn't safely get into our bathroom. So, staying in the apartment seemed like a bad plan. We wound up calling 911 and getting an ambulance.</p><p>Thankfully, I was able to choose hospitals, so I went to NYU. All of my doctors are in the NYU system, and their Neurology program is ranked top in the country, so I figured that was the best place to go.</p><p>That was Thursday morning. There were no rooms, so I stayed in the ER until Friday afternoon, but other than that, care was excellent. In total, I had a spine MRI, CT scan, chest X-Ray, lumbar puncture (would not recommend that), and at least 10 blood test draws. Friday afternoon, I was moved into the 2nd best hospital room I've ever seen, and only because the other one was 2-3 times as big. Everything else about this room was better. The view, 65" TV, tablet for controlling the TV, ordering food, controlling lights and temp, etc.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Tv and window" src="/assets/images/tv_window-2a83898e00aedd034d796548b6fdfe35.jpg" width="2016" height="1512" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Night view" src="/assets/images/nightview-358748d32e061773f88c14f10aadb020.jpg" width="2016" height="1512" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Sunrise" src="/assets/images/morning_sunrise-09b618cd70c8e95906041e2527296b07.jpg" width="2016" height="1512" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Tablet" src="/assets/images/tablet-37a6d929a5d90b3b5a5042fabd1c9540.jpg" width="2016" height="1512" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Originally I was going to stay through Tuesday, but recovery was so quick they let me out Sunday. While I was certainly happy to go home, by Sunday I was basically fine. That room would be pretty amazing if you could get around easily :)</p><p>Anyway, after all that, the diagnosis was CIDP. It's relatively rare, and probably caused by whatever respiratory virus I had mid December. I had 3 infusions of IVIG: Friday night, Saturday night, and Sunday afternoon. After the first one, Saturday morning, my hands were useful again, and I could get around with the walker. On Sunday, I could walk without the walker.</p><p>On Tuesday, 2/28, I went to that Neurology appointment. The doctor said it might be AIDP, which means I may be done with treatment altogether. My hand and leg strength as of Wednesday, 6 days after the fall, seemed completely back to normal (except atrophy, which should be built back up quickly). </p><p>So, Thursday, can't walk or use my hands. 5-6 days later, back to normal. It's been a wild couple weeks.</p><p>Please donate blood. That's how they make IVIG. Huge thanks to the NYU medical team.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello!]]></title>
            <link>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/02/16/Well-Hello</link>
            <guid>https://kpgalligan.github.io/blog/2023/02/16/Well-Hello</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I no longer remember how many "new blog" posts I've written, but here's another one.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I no longer remember how many "new blog" posts I've written, but here's another one.</p><p>Over the past year I've learned quite a bit about <a href="https://docusaurus.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Docusaurus</a>. It's safe to say at this point that I love it. Markdown everything! Easy react extensions. Open source. It's fantastic.</p><p>We're slowly moving Touchlab open source repos to Docusaurus. Besides better formatting and navigation, we also do a little trick to place the latest library version directly in the docs.</p><p>The home page for this site is just react with tailwind as the CSS library. It would be great if Docusaurus had a tailwind template, but for now I've hacked everything to let the two systems reasonably coexist.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>